Have you ever asked yourself what would
happen if you grew a human brain in an
animal brain in a lab and fuse them
together? I did and it turns out they do
better than human brains alone. I will
explain.
Just in case you're not familiar, you
can grow a tiny version of a human brain
in a lab. This is called a brain
organoid. It can be done from skin cells
turned into stem cells. There are a wide
variety of reasons why you'd want to do
this. One of them is computation. Yeah,
because brain organoids can operate as a
form of AI. The other one is medicine
because these can be treatments for
strokes and have had very good results
for mouse models and even Simeon models.
It just hasn't been done in humans yet
and there's a good reason for that
because you don't really want to mess
with your brain. While we have
transplanted them into other animals and
had very good results, we still want to
know what's going to happen with them
when they're grown before we transplant
them into a human being. A lot of stem
cell research has been done with trying
to use stem cells to heal strokes, but
it's not very effective. It does better
if you grow them into a little brain
before moving them. Researchers have run
into a lot of barriers when it comes to
growing them independently of a brain
because inside of a mouse brain, they do
grow. They make projections all the way
through the brain. They repair damage.
They effectively act as a baby brain.
Yes, they are highly immature brain
tissue, but because of that, they can
integrate and they can mature and become
a functional part of a mouse's brain. Of
course, there are a lot of ethical
implications to this because this is
humanizing animals. It's taking human
parts and integrating them and we tend
to apply human morality a little bit
higher than we do with other so-called
lesser animals. Keeping them alive and
active and functional is very difficult
inside of a Petri dish in part because
they don't have a lot to do and our
brains need something to do.
So, why not co-culture them? And yes,
that is the idea. Lump together a brain
organoid with a slice of mature mouse
brain.
That is exactly what these researchers
did and it turns out they live longer
and do better. These were human
microglial cells. This might seem like a
slightly strange idea because microglial
cells are part of your brain's immune
system and while your brain doesn't
really have that aggressive an system,
you really wouldn't want it to. It does
have it, and that makes up about 10% of
your brain's total cells.
They integrate just fine with something
that is not human, although that is not
really the point of this study. They're
not just trying to see if we can make
chimeras. They're trying to observe
brains over the long term. Having more
mature brains gives us a platform to
study human beings in something that is
not a live human being. I don't know a
good way to say this other than brains
just need something to do in order to
remain functional. That does make sense
to you, especially if you think about
human beings. We need to use our muscles
or they'll atrophy. Our brains also need
to be used in order to create neural
pathways and maintain them. Otherwise,
you will forget, and it is the reason
that I don't know how to do long
division. Theoretically, I knew it some
point, and I could probably learn it
again, but I also have no reason to do
so.
A lot of people find this research
generally creepy, and I do understand
this because the brain is so integral to
what we are. If there ever was a soul,
it would probably be present in the
brain.
The idea of taking something that makes
us human and transplanting it into an
animal should make you uncomfortable,
and maybe so when it comes to growing
parts of humans in a laboratory. This is
one of the reasons that researchers are
hesitant to call brain organoids
sentient or conscious. Well, yes, some
researchers have claimed sentience. If
the public has a major backlash against
this research, it could hamper it for
decades to come.
We don't understand sentience or
consciousness enough to even really
apply it to anything. We understand our
own experiences ideally inside our own
heads, but we cannot apply that to
others because we do not know what their
experience is like. If we start applying
this to neuronal cultures in a dish,
then, well, we're being dishonest, to be
fair.
Instead, I propose a middle ground. We
cannot make claims that we just can't
defend. So, we're not able to say that
these things are definitely conscious,
and we're also not able to say that they
will never be conscious, especially when
we are loving them together, embodying
them in video games, and robots, and
other animals.
We can make them larger. We can make
them live longer. Should that research
necessarily be done? I'm not sure. I
really do think it should be
investigated as a treatment for strokes.
I'm not wild about biological neural
networks as a replacement for
computation with AI. It just feels wrong
and I know I have no good reason to say
that. So, it's a good thing I'm not in
charge.
I really hope you've enjoyed this. I
will keep you up to date. You have no
choice. Follow for more.